<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<maintainer type="person">
		<email>lssndrbarbieri@gmail.com</email>
		<name>Alessandro Barbieri</name>
	</maintainer>
	<longdescription lang="en">
MRNet is a customizable, high-performance software infrastructure for
building scalable tools and applications.  It supports efficient 
multicast and data aggregation functionality using a tree of processes 
between the tool's front-end and back-ends.  MRNet-based tools may use 
these internal processes to distribute many important tool activities, 
for example to reduce data analysis time and keep tool front-end loads 
manageable.

MRNet-based tool components communicate across logical channels called
streams. At MRNet internal processes, filters are bound to these streams to
synchronize and aggregate dataflows. Using filters, MRNet can efficiently
compute averages, sums, and other more complex aggregations and analyses
on tool data. MRNet also supports facilities that allow tool developers
dynamically load new tool-specific filters into the system.

Features:
* Flexible tool organization: MRNet does not dictate the organization of
MRNet and tool processes, so MRNet-based tools can tailor MRNet's
configuration to the requirements of the tool and its target environment.

* Scalable, flexible data aggregation:  MRNet provides a set of built-in
filters for traditional data aggregation operations like averages, sums,
and data concatenation.  MRNet also supports custom, dynamically-loaded
filters for tool-specific aggregations.

* High-bandwidth communication: Internally, MRNet transfers data using an 
efficient, packed binary representation. Zero-copy data paths are used 
whenever possible to reduce data transfer latency.

* Scalable multicast: MRNet supports efficient multicast to reduce the cost
of delivering tool control messages to tool back-ends.

* Multiple concurrent data channels: MRNet supports multiple logical
channels of data between tool components. Multiple aggregation and
multicast operations may be in progress simultaneously.

* Open source licensing.
	</longdescription>
	<use>
		<flag name="libi">Use libi as tree instantiation method instead of ssh</flag>
		<flag name="threadsafe">Build threasafe version of lightweight MRNet and XPlat libraries</flag>
		<flag name="slurm">Use slurm as libi tree instantiation method instead of ssh</flag>
	</use>
	<upstream>
		<bugs-to>https://github.com/dyninst/mrnet/issues</bugs-to>
		<remote-id type="github">dyninst/mrnet</remote-id>
	</upstream>
</pkgmetadata>
