<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<upstream>
		<bugs-to>https://github.com/intel/intel-cmt-cat/issues</bugs-to>
		<remote-id type="github">intel/intel-cmt-cat</remote-id>
	</upstream>
	<maintainer type="person">
		<email>lssndrbarbieri@gmail.com</email>
		<name>Alessandro Barbieri</name>
	</maintainer>
	<longdescription lang="en">
Overview
========

This software package provides basic support for
Intel(R) Resource Director Technology (Intel(R) RDT) including:
Cache Monitoring Technology (CMT), Memory Bandwidth Monitoring (MBM),
Cache Allocation Technology (CAT), Code and Data Prioritization (CDP)
and Memory Bandwidth Allocation (MBA).

In principle, the software programs the technologies via
Model Specific Registers (MSR) on a hardware thread basis.
MSR access is arranged via a standard operating system driver:
msr on Linux and cpuctl on FreeBSD. In the most common architectural
implementations, presence of the technologies is detected via the
CPUID instruction.

In a limited number of special cases where CAT is not architecturally
supported on a particular SKU (but instead a non-architectural
(model-specific) implementation exists) it can be detected via brand
string. This brand string is read from CPUID and compared to a table
of known-supported SKUs. If needed, a final check is to probe the
specific MSR’s to discover hardware capabilities, however it is
recommended that CPUID enumeration should be used wherever possible.

From software version v1.0.0 the library adds option to use Intel(R) RDT via
available OS interfaces (perf and resctrl on Linux). The library detects
presence of these interfaces and allows to select the preferred one through
a configuration option.
As the result, existing tools like 'pqos' or 'rdtset' can also be used
to manage Intel(R) RDT in an OS compatible way. MSR interface remains
the default option for now. 'pqos' tool wrappers have been added to help with
the interface selection. 'pqos-os' and 'pqos-msr' for OS and MSR interface
operations respectively.

PID API compile time option has been removed and the APIs are always available.
Note that proper operation of these APIs depends on availability and
selection of OS interface.
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
