<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "https://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<maintainer type="person">
		<email>liaoyuan@gmail.com</email>
		<name>Yuan Liao</name>
	</maintainer>
	<longdescription>
		DOSBox-X is a fork of DOSBox. The main focus of DOSBox is just on
		running DOS games, whereas DOSBox-X goes further than this: while it
		"retains compatibility with the wide base of DOS games and DOS gaming
		DOSBox was designed for", it is built to also run DOS applications,
		Windows 3.x, Windows 9x series, and software written for those versions
		of Windows. In particular, Windows 98 runs with superb stability on
		DOSBox-X, which DOSBox cannot achieve yet.

		DOSBox-X also ships more user-friendly features than DOSBox, including
		a drop-down menu system for easier alteration to emulation parameters
		and access to the emulator's functions, a graphical configuration tool
		for modifying the configuration file, saving and loading the emulator's
		state, creation of new disk image files, support for directly mounting
		hard disk images with partitions formatted with the FAT32 file system,
		and many more.
	</longdescription>
	<upstream>
		<doc>https://dosbox-x.com/wiki/</doc>
		<remote-id type="github">joncampbell123/dosbox-x</remote-id>
	</upstream>
	<use>
		<flag name="X">
			Enable X11 integration for better fullscreening functionality
		</flag>
		<flag name="debug">
			Enable the internal debugger of this program
		</flag>
		<flag name="ffmpeg">
			Enable MPEG.TS + H.264 video capture format support
			via <pkg>media-video/ffmpeg</pkg>
		</flag>
		<flag name="fluidsynth">
			Enable FluidSynth to be used as the MIDI synthesizer
		</flag>
		<flag name="opengl">
			Enable OpenGL as a video system to use for output
		</flag>
		<flag name="png">
			Enable screenshot and video capture support
			via <pkg>media-libs/libpng</pkg>
		</flag>
		<flag name="slirp">
			Enable the SLIRP back-end for network adapter emulation
		</flag>
		<flag name="truetype">
			Enable TrueType font (TTF) output and printing support
			via <pkg>media-libs/freetype</pkg>
		</flag>
	</use>
</pkgmetadata>
