<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
    <maintainer type="person">
        <email>lssndrbarbieri@gmail.com</email>
        <name>Alessandro Barbieri</name>
    </maintainer>
    <upstream>
        <bugs-to>https://github.com/mfem/mfem/issues</bugs-to>
        <remote-id type="github">mfem/mfem</remote-id>
    </upstream>
    <use>
        <flag name="benchmark">Enables support for Google Benchmark, a library to support the benchmarking of functions</flag>
        <flag name="codipack">Enable automatic differentiation using the CoDiPack library</flag>
        <flag name="ginkgo">Enable MFEM functionality based on the Ginkgo library</flag>
        <flag name="hip">Enables support for AMD devices in MFEM</flag>
        <flag name="metis">Enable the use of the METIS library</flag>
        <flag name="exceptions">Enable the use of exceptions. In particular, modifies the default behavior when errors are encountered: throw an exception, instead of aborting.</flag>
        <flag name="mpfr">Enables the use of MPFR in MFEM, e.g. for precise computation of 1D quadrature rules</flag>
        <flag name="mumps">Enable MFEM functionality based on the MUMPS library. Currently, this option adds the class MUMPSSolver (a parallel sparse direct solver).</flag>
        <flag name="petsc">Enable MFEM linear and non-linear solvers, preconditioners, time integrators and other features based on the PETSc package.</flag>
        <flag name="slepc">Enable MFEM eigensolvers based on the SLEPc package.</flag>
        <flag name="sparse">Enable MFEM functionality based on the SuiteSparse library. Currently, this option adds the classes UMFPackSolver and KLUSolver (both sparse serial direct solvers).</flag>
        <flag name="strumpack">Enable MFEM functionality based on the STRUMPACK sparse direct solver and preconditioner through the STRUMPACKSolver and STRUMPACKRowLocMatrix classes.</flag>
        <flag name="sundials">Enable MFEM time integrators and non-linear solvers based on the SUNDIALS library.</flag>
        <flag name="superlu">Enable MFEM functionality based on the SuperLU_DIST library. Currently, this option adds the classes SuperLUSolver (a parallel sparse direct solver) and SuperLURowLocMatrix a distributed CSR matrix class needed by SuperLU.</flag>
        <flag name="threadsafe">Use thread-safe implementation for some classes/methods. This comes at the cost of extra memory allocation and de-allocation.</flag>
    </use>
</pkgmetadata>
